# **ALESSANDRO BARRETO**

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | CIVIL EGINEER

### **ABOUT**

Technology enthusiast, proactive and constantly seeking new challenges for personal and professional development. I have 2 graduations in Systems Analysis and Development and Civil Engineering. I have 6 years of experience in the market, working in areas such as modeling, development, data analysis and commercial management. I currently work as a software developer in Europe.

**KNOWLEDGE** 

Computing

Data Analysis

Programming

Automation

Web Development

• Comercial Management

• Agile Methodologies

Civil Engineering

Environment

• Client Communication

### **SKILLS**

### **TOOLS**

- React
- Next.js
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Python
- HTML
- CSS SASS
- Node
- Material UI
- Redux
- Express
- MongoDB
- Docker
- Git
- Microsoft Office

#### **LANGUAGES**

Portuguese

English

Spanish

00000

00000

00000

### **CONTACT:**

✓ alessandrobarreto1201@gmail.com

(+351) 912-765-320

Lisbon, Portugal

in linkedin.com/in/alessandro--barreto

github.com/AlessandroBarreto

alessandro-barreto.netlify.app/

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Full Stack Developer**

BMW Group | Dec 2021 - Present

• Front Typescript; Frameworks/Libs: Next|S, Theme UI, Axios, Context API;

 Back: Typescript; Frameworks/Libs: Node, AWS lambda;

- Testing: Jest, React-testing-library;
- **DB**: Commercetools;
- **Devops**: Docker, AWS, MacOS, Git, Postman, CI/CD, Kibana;
- Scrum

### **Full Stack Developer**

J&A Multi-sector Smart Solutions | May 2021 - Dec 2021

- Front Javascript, Typescript; Frameworks/Libs: React, Angular, React Router, Material UI, Axios;
- Back: Javascript, Typescript, Python; Frameworks/Libs: Node, Express, Flask, Selenium;
- Testing: Jest, React-testing-library;
- DB: Mongo;
- Devops: Docker, Google Workspace, Bitbucket, Linux, Windows, Git, Postman;
- Scrum

### Front End Developer

Aquarela Advanced Analytics | Jun 2020 - May 2021

- Front: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Figma; Frameworks/Libs: React, D3, Material UI, React Router, React Hook Form, ContextAPI, Bootstrap, Axios;
- Testing: Jest, Enzyme;
- DevOps: Docker, Gitlab, Jenkins, Git, Linux, Postman, VPN, Clickup, Google Workspace;
- Scrum:
- Documentation.

# **EDUCATION**

### **Estacio University**

Degree in Systems Analysis and Development | 2020 - 2023

# **Federal University of Santa Catarina**

Degree in Civil Engineering: Sanitation and Environment | 2013 - 2019

# **REFERENCES**

Gilherme Girol

CTO | Sanova Water Management Solutions E-mail: guilherme.girol@sanova.com.br

Lucas Lovato Software Developer | Clevertech

E-mail: Lucas.lovato@clevertech.biz

Sarah Pfaffenzeller Software Developer | TheoremOne

E-mail: sarahizabelp@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Full Stack Developer**

BMW Group | Dec 2021 - Present

• I worked in the maintenance, implementation and testing for the 3 e-commerce platforms of BMW and MINI cooper (cars, products and services) in several countries. The main technology used was NextJS with server side rendering, state management, testing with jest and AWS ecosystem tools. Commercetools was the platform for creating and managing products and orders;

### **Full Stack Developer**

J&A Multi-sector Smart Solutions | May 2021 - Dec 2021

• I worked with front end tools like Angular and wordpress to maintain the websites of J&A Holding companies. I participated in the construction of several robots using Python, pandas, selenium, requests, HTML and CSS for the processes automation and email campaigns of the company and creation of screens using React, APIs in Node and express for the consumption of these robots, together with MongoDB. Containerization of the applications using Docker, Docker Compose and Linux servers. Construction of the website with the new identity of Fontes Promotora website, using React and covering the desktop and mobile versions;

### **Front End Developer**

Aquarela Advanced Analytics | Jun 2020 - May 2021

• I worked on the front end (React) together with the back end to design an internal platform for manage and search projects, stacks, tools and company workers. Then I worked on the front-end of the Fras-le (automotive segment) company's artificial intelligence project, focusing on building screens for data visualization, using React, D3, tests with Jest and Enzyme, documentation of processes and I started experimenting tools like Docker, MongoDB and Python for the back end. Finally, I worked on the construction of an ontology finder plataform using React;

### **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE**

### **Tech Mentor**

Technovation | Fevereiro de 2021 - Abril de 2021

• Technovation is an international program that encourages children around the world to learn and apply the skills needed to solve real world problems through technology. I acted as a mentor in a team of 4 children between 12 and 14 years old, participating in workshops, meetings and planning to create an environmental awareness app as a final product of the project.